

Experienced Data Analyst primarily functioning as a data scientist/business intelligence developer. In my current role I focus on effectively sourcing, processing, and displaying data in order to transform it into easily digestible visualizations that provide the foundation for effective decision making.

#### CONTACT

anthonypoluch@gmail.com (484) 866-7744

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Pittsburgh College of Business Administration

Bachelor of Science - Business Administration April 2018

**Triple Major:** 3.52 GPA Business Information Systems Supply Chain Management Marketing

#### **PROFICIENCIES**

Tableau Desktop/Server
Alteryx Designer/Server
Power BI
SQL
VBA
Toad
Data Analysis
Data Visualization
Data Sourcing and Processing
Automation
Visio
Microsoft Office Suite

# **Anthony Poluch**

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Highmark Health, Data Reporting Analyst

June 2020 - Present

- Used Tableau as a front-end BI tool and Alteryx as a back end data sourcing, processing, and automation tool to design and develop workflows, dashboards, and self-service data
- Tools: Tableau, Alteryx, Python, Excel

Highmark Health, Emerging Leaders Program Associate

June 2018 - June 2020

Rotational program consisting of four 6-month rotations in various data analyst roles

#### • Service Portfolio and Analytics Reporting

Jan 2020 - Present

- Redesigned team's current reporting data sourcing, structuring, and processing using Toad for SQL Server and Alteryx to consolidate/centralize it
- Developed various Tableau dashboards to communicate financial and utilization data
- Tools/Languages: Alteryx, Toad for SQL Server, Tableau, Power BI, SQL

#### • Demand Capacity and Resource Management

Jun 2019 - Jan 2020

- Developed and automated data sourcing, structuring, and processing infrastructure using Alteryx and Toad for Oracle for team's data needs
- Developed Tableau dashboards combining resource forecasted time data, resource availability, and resource skills data
- Tools/Languages: Alteryx, Toad for Oracle, Tableau, SQL

## • Business Management Analytics

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

- Developed and maintained tableau dashboards for leadership combining data on resources, finances, and time
- o Tools: Tableau, Excel

#### • Release Management

Jun 2018 - Jan 2019

- Produced reporting on new software releases and ensured all related documentation was completed for auditing purposes
- o Automated excel reporting using VBA and various excel formulas
- Tools/Languages: Excel, VBA, Cognos

#### **HM Health Solution, Business Technical Analyst**

May 2017 - June 2018

- Provided support in corporate initiative to develop a standard for documentation of systems and processes critical to increasing efficiency and providing updated technical information
- Executed agile methodology using tools such as Jira, Confluence, and Lucid Charts to aid in team communication, coordination, and planning
- Tools: Agile, Lucid Charts, Jira, Confluence

## **University of Pittsburgh,** Grants Development Intern

Sep 2016 - May 2017

- Performed data analysis, cleansing, and created visualizations using Tableau, Power BI, OpenRefine and other data visualization tool to discover funding opportunities
- Tools: Tableau, Power BI, Excel

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Alteryx Designer Core Certification (May 2020 May 2022)
- Tableau Desktop Certified Associate (October 2020 October 2022)
- Certified Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt (Apr 2019)